Fred Starner Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Fred Starner Collection
1966 - 1985
NPkMC-224-295
6.5 Linear Feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Fred Starner
"Banjo Fred" Starner was a Professor of Economics at Drew University in New Jersey, but was dismissed due to his political activism. He was heavily involved in the Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, a project conceived by Seeger in which a ship would be constructed through community funding and sponsor environmental and folk education programs. He helped with the initial fundraising and was on the ship’s maiden voyage in 1969 as a crew member. Starner was involved in a number of other projects as well. Starner was fascinated by hobo culture. A significant amount of effort towards the end of his life was focused on producing the documentary film "That’s the Ticket Road Hog: The Hobo’s Song", released in 2009,
Collection Overview
The Fred Starner Collection is a collection comprised largely of administrative files concerning the Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc., but it also contains newspaper clipping scrapbooks, posters, flyers, a pamphlet, a program, a photograph, and handwritten poems and lyrics to both traditional and original folk songs. Also included in the collection are Starner’s notes on Clearwater, which he began to compile for a book tentatively titled The Singers and the Boat.
Acquisitions Informantion
The Fred Starner Collection was gathered by Fred Starner, largely in preparation for a book he intended to write on the Hudson River Sloop Restoration tentatively entitled The Singers and the Boat. Marist College purchased the collection in 2015.
Historical Note
"Banjo Fred" Starner was born George Frederick Starner to James and Charlotte Starner in Toledo, Ohio in 1937. He attended Oberlin College, where he completed a Bachelor’s degree in Economics. While at Oberlin, he was first drawn to folk music after attending a Pete Seeger concert, an experience which inspired Starner to learn five-string banjo, and later twelve-string guitar. Later, he received a Master’s from the University of Michigan and a Ph.D. in Economics from Ohio State University. He became a Professor of Economics at Drew University in New Jersey, but was dismissed due to his political activism. He was heavily involved in the Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, a project conceived by Seeger in which a ship would be constructed through community funding and sponsor environmental and folk education programs. He helped with the initial fundraising by putting on a concert series. Starner was on the ship’s maiden voyage in 1969 from Maine to New York as a crew member with his wife Barbara, whom he married in 1962, serving as the cook. In all, he was involved with the organization from 1968-1974, even serving on the Board of Directors for three years in the 1970s.
Starner was involved in a number of other projects as well. He worked on a ten-part PBS documentary series entitled The Oleanna Trail in 1972 about folk music. In 1974, he began teaching Economics at Wisconsin-La Crosse. While at La Crosse, he helped found the Great River Traditional Music and Crafts Festival, which continued for almost ten years. He moved to California to teach economics at multiple community colleges while continuing to perform and write songs in 1987.
Starner was also fascinated by hobo culture, an interest that apparently began when he recalled his mother giving money and meals to the hobos that passed by their house. A significant amount of effort towards the end of his life was focused on producing the documentary film "That’s the Ticket Road Hog: The Hobo’s Song", released in 2009, with material drawn from his compilation of the songs, poetry, and personal stories that he collected from firsthand conversations.
He died of complications of pneumonia and chronic lung disease in Los Angeles on Sunday, October 25, 2009 at age 72.
Restrictions to Access
There are no restrictions on this collection
Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc. Collection, 1965 - 2000
This collection is divided into six series: 1) Fred Starner's Personal Materials, 2) Hudson River Sloop Restoration Administrative Files, 3) Music, 4) Publicity Materials, 5) Scrapbooks, and 6) Miscellany
- 1. Fred Starner’s Personal Materials, 1; Box: 1
  - Month-at-a-Glance planner [also contains contacts, lullaby lyrics, and draft statement on government violence], 1971 (Folder 1, Box 1)
  - Notes on collected materials, undated (Folder 2, Box 1)
  - Notes on Hudson River Sloop Restorations's Administration, undated (Folder 3, Box 1)
  - The Singers and the Boat: Project [notes for book draft], undated (Folder 4, Box 1)
- 2. Hudson River Sloop Restoration Administrative Files, 1966 - 1985; 2; Boxes: 1 - 3
  - Proposal for the Construction, Use and Maintenance of a Replica of a "Hudson River Sloop", 1966 (Folder 5, Box 1)
  - Board Meetings, 16 September 1967- 20 October 1967 (Folder 6, Box 1)
  - Correspondence from R. B. Weber to Pete Seegar [sic], 24-Aug-67 (Folder 7, Box 1)
  - Special Newsletter, circa 23 September 1967- 5 November 1967 (Folder 8, Box 1)
  - Correspondence from Helene Duffy to John Jones, circa 5 November 1967 (Folder 9, Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Professor Richard Wilkie and Helene "Cookie" Duffy, 15 November 1967- 27 November 1967 (Folder 10, Box 1)
  - Board Meeting Materials- Minutes and Summaries, 10 March 1968- 28 August 1968 (Folder 11, Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Helene "Cookie" Duffy and Professor Richard Wilkie, 5 January 1968- 23 May 1968 (Folder 12, Box 1)
  - Hudson River Sloop Restoration to Exhibit at N.Y. Boat Show, circa 10 February 1968- 13 February 1968 (Folder 13, Box 1)
  - Correspondence from Helene "Cookie" Duffy to Bill Spence, 22-Jul-68 (Folder 14, Box 1)
  - Correspondence from Pete [Seeger] to Dick [Richard Wilkie], 1968 (Folder 15, Box 1)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 3 June 1969- 7 December 1969 (Folder 16, Box 1)
  - North River Navigator- Progress Report, 18-Feb-69 (Folder 17, Box 1)
  - Letter to volunteer crew members, signed by Pete Seeger, Alexander Saunders, Fred and Barbara Starner, and William Taggart, 29-May-69 (Folder 18, Box 1)
  - Board Meeting Materials- Minutes, Notes, Agenda, Memos, Treasurer's Report, 18 February 1970- 15 November 1970 (Folder 19, Box 1)
  - Lower Hudson River Basin Abatement Progress pollution report, Jan-70 (Folder 20, Box 1)
  - Correspondence from Joan Tauss to Fred [Starner], 11-Mar-70 (Folder 21, Box 1)
  - Letter of resignation from Hal Cohen to Directors of HRSR [Hudson River Sloop Restoration], 18-Sep-70 (Folder 22, Box 1)
  - Letter of resignation from Vice-President Donald R. Presutti to Board of Directors, 23-Sep-70 (Folder 23, Box 1)
  - Correspondence from William Taggart to Richard Wilkie, 21-Oct-70 (Folder 24, Box 1)
  - Letter of resignation from Richard A. Dwelley, 21-Oct-70 (Folder 25, Box 1)
  - Correspondence from Kathy L. Paulus to Jimmy Collin regarding wood carving of Pete Seeger for "White Elephant" Auction, 28-Oct-70 (Folder 26, Box 1)
  - Letter from President Harry Dobson to incoming board members, 8-Dec-70 (Folder 27, Box 1)
  - Fred Starner- "Suggestion; The need for two individuals in the HRSR office", circa 1970-1971 (Folder 28, Box 1)
  - Notes on Organization and Budget, circa 1970-1971 (Folder 29, Box 1)
  - Board Meeting Materials- Minutes, President's Report, Treasurer's Report, Meeting Notice, Dom Arone's Suggested Organization Chart, 10 January 1971- 21 November 1971 (Folder 30, Box 1)
  - Extracts- Directions, 10 January 1971- 12 December 1971 (Folder 31, Box 1)
  - Call to Action by Fred Starner, circa 4 February 1971 (Folder 32, Box 1)
  - Correspondence from Robert G. Kimble, President of Kimbo Educational Records, to Fred Starner and Fred Kirkpatrick regarding Black Culture in Story and Song project [found in Month-at-a-Glance planner, 1971], 19-Mar-71 (Folder 33, Box 1)
  - Correspondence from John Corfias to Mill Malloy of Dyke College regarding "Clearwater" Project, 23-Apr-71 (Folder 34, Box 1)
  - Memo from Harry Dobson to Board Members regarding resignation of Bill Taggart, 27-May-71 (Folder 35, Box 1)
  - Correspondence from Dominick Pirone to Fred Starner, 25-Aug-71 (Folder 1, Box 2)
  - Letter to Dom[inick Pirone, Executive Director], 13-Sep-71 (Folder 2, Box 2)
  - Press release regarding board elected 7 November 1971, 12 Novermber 1971 (Folder 3, Box 2)
  - Report of the Executive Director [Dominick Pirone], 21-Nov-71 (Folder 4, Box 2)
  - Correspondence between John M. Burns, III and Dr. Fred Starner, 23 November 1971- 2 December 1971 (Folder 5, Box 2)
  - Notice of Special Meeting, circa 12 December 1971 (Folder 6, Box 2)
  - "Three New Jersey Based Hudson Polluters Named", 15-Dec-71 (Folder 7, Box 2)
  - Newsletter, Dec-71 (Folder 8, Box 2)
  - Sailing Schedule for Clearwater 1971 Season (Folder 9, Box 2)
  - Board Meeting Materials- Minutes, Agenda, Memos, Operation Manager's report [includes information on resignations of Captain Reed Haslam and Board Member David M. Seymour], 9 January 1972- 17 December 1972 (Folder 10, Box 2)
  - Crew Member Assignment Letter, 20-Apr-72 (Folder 11, Box 2)
  - News Brief, Jun-72 (Folder 12, Box 2)
  - Letter from Reed Haslam to Board Members regarding his resignation, 19-Sep-72 (Folder 13, Box 2)
  - Clearwater Schedule, 1972 (Folder 14, Box 2)
  - Board Elections of 1970 and 1972, 1970-1972 (Folder 15, Box 2)
  - Board Meetings, circa 25 February 1973- 16 December 1973 (Folder 16, Box 2)
  - Grant Application to New York State Council on the Arts draft proposal prepared by [Helene] Cookie Duffy, Operations Manager, 16-Feb-73 (Folder 17, Box 2)
  - Clearwater Schedule, 1973 (Folder 18, Box 2)
  - Board Meeting Minutes and Summary, 11 December 1974, 27 December 1974 (Folder 19, Box 2)
  - Correspondence from John Harris-Cronin, Ainslie Gilligan, Joseph R. Phillips, Janice Hornbach, Maria Colavito, and R. Dennis O'Leary to board members regarding intoxication at meetings, 13-Dec-74 (Folder 20, Box 2)
  - Report to the Board of Director from the Office Staff, 13-Dec-74 (Folder 21, Box 2)
  - Board Elections of 1974 (Folder 22, Box 2)
  - Board Meeting Materials, 8 January 1975- 31 December 1975 (Folder 23, Box 2)
  - Proposed HRSR 1975 Budget, 8-Jan-75 (Folder 24, Box 2)
  - Status of current HRSR activities related to fundraising therough grants from private foundations and corporations, 17-Jan-75 (Folder 25, Box 2)
  - Fundraising Letters, circa 12 March 1975- 21 March 1975 (Folder 26, Box 2)
  - Notes from Fund-Raising Committee, 24-Jun-75 (Folder 27, Box 2)
  - H. R. S. R. Financial Position, December 1974- June 1975, Jun-75 (Folder 28, Box 2)
  - Correspondence from Walter H. Schwane [President] to Russell Train, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, 11-Aug-75 (Folder 29, Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Michael Ross, Superintendent of Public Schools of Jersey City, and Walter H. Schwane, President, HRSR, regarding Captain Frank Fulchiero, 14 August 1975- 25 August 1975 (Folder 30, Box 2)
  - Letter of resignation from J. R. Phillips, 9-Sep-75 (Folder 31, Box 2)
  - PCB Controversy- "Of PCB ppms FROM GE and a SNAFU from EPA and DEC", Nov-75 (Folder 32, Box 2)
  - Clearwater Annual Report, 1-Dec-75 (Folder 33, Box 2)
  - Fundraising letter with Toshi and Peter Seeger's return address, circa 1975 (Folder 34, Box 2)
  - Board Meetings, 18 January 1976- 5 December 1976 (Folder 35, Box 2)
  - Clearwater Maintenance [includes letter from Pete Seeger referenced in board minutes from 7 March 1976], 3 January 1976- 19 April 1976 (Folder 36, Box 2)
  - Correspondence from [Director] Walter P. Bowers, II to Angela McGill [sic] [President], 16-Jan-76 (Folder 37, Box 2)
  - PCB Controversy New York Times articles- "2 State Officials Split in Controversy Over Discharge of PCB's Into Hudson" and "What Price Jobs?", 16 January 1976, 26 January 1976 (Folder 38, Box 2)
  - Statement of Introduction to Hudson River Sloop Restoration's Programs, 1-Mar-76 (Folder 1, Box 3)
  - Minutes of the Environmental Action Committee, 26-Apr-76 (Folder 2, Box 3)
  - "The Talk of the Town" in The New Yorker, cicrca summer 1976 (Folder 3, Box 3)
  - Dave Seymour's Hike for the Hudson River, Aug-76 (Folder 4, Box 3)
  - "Clearwater Calls on EPA to Rais PCB Money to $10 M[illion]" and Correspondence from Angela Magill [President] to Russel Train {Environmental Protection Agency], 10-Sep-76 (Folder 5, Box 3)
  - Report of the [By-Laws Review] Committee to the Board of Directors of the Hudson River Sloop Restoration, Inc., circa 4 November 1976 (Folder 6, Box 3)
  - Correspondence from [Board Member] Walt to Angela Magill [President], 11-Dec-76 (Folder 7, Box 3)
  - 1976 Annual Hudson River Sloop Restoration, Inc. Meeting, circa December 1976 (Folder 8, Box 3)
  - Membership and Endowment Fund Proposals, 1976 (Folder 9, Box 3)
  - Weekly Highlights, 1976 (Folder 10, Box 3)
  - Board Meeting Materials- Minutes, Memo from President Angela Magill, Financial Report, 9 January 1977- 20 November 1977 (Folder 11, Box 3)
  - Clearwater Financial Program, 15-Mar-77 (Folder 12, Box 3)
  - Monthly Membership Reports and Weekly Highlights, March 1977- April 1977 (Folder 13, Box 3)
  - Lobbying and Maintenance of Tax Exempt Status, 1-Apr-77 (Folder 14, Box 3)
  - Clearwater Fall Seminar [including committee outlines], circa 1 October 1977- 2 October 1977 (Folder 15, Box 3)
  - Memo to the Board of Directors from Angela Magill- fundraising appeal, 23-Nov-77 (Folder 16, Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting of the Clearwater, 4-Dec-77 (Folder 17, Box 3)
  - 1977 Clearwater Treasurer's Report, Dec-77 (Folder 18, Box 3)
  - List of Board of Directors Members, 1977 (Folder 19, Box 3)
  - Board Meeting Materials- Minutes and Treasurer's Reports, 22 January 1978- 17 December 1978 (Folder 20, Box 3)
  - Anti-Nuclear Power Policy, circa 24 June 1978- 25 June 1978 (Folder 21, Box 3)
  - Fundraising Plan- Memo, Mailings, and Corporation List, circa 11 August 1978- December 1978 (Folder 22, Box 3)
  - 1978 Clearwater Treasurer's Report- For Nine Months Ending, 31-Aug-78 (Folder 23, Box 3)
  - 1978 Clearwater Annual Meeting, 24-Sep-78 (Folder 24, Box 3)
  - Executive Director's Report, 15-Oct-78 (Folder 25, Box 3)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 25 February 1979- 18 August 1979 (Folder 26, Box 3)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 22 September 1984- 18 November 1984 (Folder 27, Box 3)
  - Sloop Club Charter Guidelines, circa 1984-1985 (Folder 28, Box 3)
  - Board Meeting Materials- Minutes, Agenda, resolution honoring Sarah L. Johnston, 11 January 1985- 25 August 1985 (Folder 29, Box 3)
- 3. Music, 3; Box: 3
  - Original Songs and Poems, undated (Folder 30, Box 3)
  - People and Work- Worker's Lib Song Booklet, 8 April 1978 (Folder 31, Box 3)
  - Traditional Songs and Poems, undated (Folder 32, Box 3)
- 4. Publicity Materials, 1969 - 1986; 4; Box: 3
  - Clearwater Posters [originals in oversize Bank A, Drawer 7], 1969- June 1982 (Folder 33, Box 3)
  - Clearwater's Great Hudson River Revival Program, 15 June 1985- 16 June 1985 (Folder 34, Box 3)
  - Flyers [originals in Music series], circa 1969 (Folder 35, Box 3)
  - "Swing Into Summer at Clearwater's Revival '86" Pamphlet, circa June 1986 (Folder 36, Box 3)
- 5. Scrapbooks, 1969; 5; Boxes: 4 - 5
  - "The Hudson Sloop Will Sail Again" in The Sunday Record Call, 16 March 1969 (Folder 1, Box 4)
  - Clearwater Launching, 12 May 1969, 16 May 1969 (Folder 2, Box 4)
  - Hudson Sloop [christened], 17 May 1969, 19 May 1969 (Folder 3, Box 4)
  - Sloop launched from South Bristol, Maine, circa 19 May 1969 (Folder 4, Box 4)
  - Clearwater articles, 19 May 1969- 6 August 1969 (Folder 5, Box 4)
  - "Pete Seeger's Magnificent Dream: Schooner "Clearwater" Is Under Sail For The First Time" in Coastal Journal, 26 June 1969 (Folder 1, Box 5)
  - "Pete Seeger: He'll Sing In Nyack After All" in The Rockland County Journal-News, 11 July 1969 (Folder 2, Box 5)
  - "Symbolic Ship, Clearwater, Due In Nyack" in The Record, 30 July 1969 (Folder 3, Box 5)
  - "Hudson Sloop Coming To Nyack" in The Rockland County Journal-News, 31 July 1969 (Folder 4, Box 5)
  - "The Clearwater" in Kennebec Journal, Augusta, 2 August 1969 (Folder 5, Box 5)
  - "Lindsay Visits a Sloop: 'Clearwater' sails on a river that isn't" in The Sunday Star-Ledger, 3 August 1969 (Folder 6, Box 5)
  - Clearwater in The Journal-News, Nyack, New York, circa 8 August 1969 (Folder 7, Box 5)
  - "'Folky' People Gather" in The Rockland County Journal-News, 9 August 1969 (Folder 8, Box 5)
  - "The Park Is Empty -The Sloop Is Gone" in The Journal-News, Nyack, New York, 11 August 1969 (Folder 9, Box 5)
  - "Sloop on Voyage to Purify Hudson Spreads Zeal and Song" in The New York Times, 28 August 1969 (Folder 10, Box 5)
  - "Hope of the Hudson" in The Conservationist, State of New York, Conservation Department, 1969 (Folder 11, Box 5)
- 6. Miscellany, 1966 - 1985; 6; Box: 3
  - Proposal for the Construction, Use and Maintenance of a Replica of a "Hudson River Sloop", 1966; 5 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Board Meetings, 16 September 1967- 20 October 1967; 6 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Correspondence from R. B. Weber to Pete Seegar [sic], 24 August 1967; 7 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Special Newsletter, circa 23 September 1967- 5 November 1967; 8 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Correspondence from Helene Duffy to John Jones, circa 5 November 1967; 9 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Correspondence between Professor Richard Wilkie and Helene "Cookie" Duffy, 15 November 1967- 27 November 1967; 10 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Board Meeting Materials- Minutes and Summaries, 10 March 1968- 28 August 1968; 11 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Correspondence between Helene "Cookie" Duffy and Professor Richard Wilkie, 5 January 1968- 23 May 1968; 12 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Hudson River Sloop Restoration to Exhibit at N.Y. Boat Show, circa 10 February 1968- 13 February 1968; 13 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Correspondence from Helene "Cookie" Duffy to Bill Spence, 22 July 1968; 14 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Correspondence from Pete [Seeger] to Dick [Richard Wilkie], 1968; 15 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 3 June 1969- 7 December 1969; 16 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - North River Navigator- Progress Report, 18 February 1968; 17 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Letter to volunteer crew members, signed by Pete Seeger, Alexander Saunders, Fred and Barbara Starner, and William Taggart, 29 May 1969; 18 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Board Meeting Materials- Minutes, Notes, Agenda, Memos, Treasurer's Report, 18 February 1970- 15 November 1970; 19 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Lower Hudson River Basin Abatement Progress pollution report, January 1970; 20 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Correspondence from Joan Tauss to Fred [Starner], 11 March 1970; 21 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Letter of resignation from Hal Cohen to Directors of HRSR [Hudson River Sloop Restoration], 18 September 1970; 22 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Letter of resignation from Vice-President Donald R. Presutti to Board of Directors, 23 September 1970; 23 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Correspondence from William Taggart to Richard Wilkie, 21 October 1970; 24 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Letter of resignation from Richard A. Dwelley, 21 October 1970; 25 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Correspondence from Kathy L. Paulus to Jimmy Collin regarding wood carving of Pete Seeger for "White Elephant" Auction, 28 October 1970; 26 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Letter from President Harry Dobson to incoming board members, 8 December 1970; 27 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Fred Starner- "Suggestion; The need for two individuals in the HRSR office", circa 1970-1971; 28 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Notes on Organization and Budget, circa 1970-1971; 29 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Board Meeting Materials- Minutes, President's Report, Treasurer's Report, Meeting Notice, Dom Arone's Suggested Organization Chart, 10 January 1971- 21 November 1971; 30 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Extracts- Directions, 10 January 1971- 12 December 1971; 31 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Call to Action by Fred Starner, circa 4 February 1971; 32 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Correspondence from Robert G. Kimble, President of Kimbo Educational Records, to Fred Starner and Fred Kirkpatrick regarding Black Culture in Story and Song project [found in Month-at-a-Glance planner, 1971], 19 March 1971; 33 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Correspondence from John Corfias to Mill Malloy of Dyke College regarding "Clearwater" Project, 23 April 1971; 34 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Memo from Harry Dobson to Board Members regarding resignation of Bill Taggart, 27 May 1971; 35 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Correspondence from Dominick Pirone to Fred Starner, 25 August 1971; 1 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Letter to Dom[inick Pirone, Executive Director], 13 September 1971; 2 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Press release regarding board elected 7 November 1971, 12 Novermber 1971; 3 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Report of the Executive Director [Dominick Pirone], 21 November 1971; 4 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Correspondence between John M. Burns, III and Dr. Fred Starner, 23 November 1971- 2 December 1971; 5 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Notice of Special Meeting, circa 12 December 1971; 6 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - "Three New Jersey Based Hudson Polluters Named", 15 December 1971; 7 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Newsletter, December 1971; 8 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Sailing Schedule for Clearwater 1971 Season, 9 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Board Meeting Materials- Minutes, Agenda, Memos, Operation Manager's report [includes information on resignations of Captain Reed Haslam and Board Member David M. Seymour], 9 January 1972- 17 December 1972; 10 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Crew Member Assignment Letter, 20 April 1972; 11 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - News Brief, June 1972; 12 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Letter from Reed Haslam to Board Members regarding his resignation, 19 September 1972; 13 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Clearwater Schedule, 1972; 14 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Board Elections of 1970 and 1972, 1970-1972; 15 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Board Meetings, circa 25 February 1973- 16 December 1973; 16 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Grant Application to New York State Council on the Arts draft proposal prepared by [Helene] Cookie Duffy, Operations Manager, 16 February 1973; 17 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Clearwater Schedule, 1973; 18 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Board Meeting Minutes and Summary, 11 December 1974, 27 December 1974; 19 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Correspondence from John Harris-Cronin, Ainslie Gilligan, Joseph R. Phillips, Janice Hornbach, Maria Colavito, and R. Dennis O'Leary to board members regarding intoxication at meetings, 13 December 1974; 20 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Report to the Board of Director from the Office Staff, 13 December 1974; 21 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Board Elections of 1974, 22 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Board Meeting Materials, 8 January 1975- 31 December 1975; 23 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Proposed HRSR 1975 Budget, 8 January 1975; 24 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Status of current HRSR activities related to fundraising therough grants from private foundations and corporations, 17 January 1975; 25 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Fundraising Letters, circa 12 March 1975- 21 March 1975; 26 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Notes from Fund-Raising Committee, 24 June 1975; 27 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - H. R. S. R. Financial Position, December 1974- June 1975, 28 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Correspondence from Walter H. Schwane [President] to Russell Train, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, 11 August 1975; 29 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Correspondence between Michael Ross, Superintendent of Public Schools of Jersey City, and Walter H. Schwane, President, HRSR, regarding Captain Frank Fulchiero, 14 August 1975- 25 August 1975; 30 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Letter of resignation from J. R. Phillips, 9 September 1975; 31 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - PCB Controversy- "Of PCB ppms FROM GE and a SNAFU from EPA and DEC", November 1975; 32 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Clearwater Annual Report, 1 December 1975; 33 (Folder 38, Box 3)